<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>theGreatWhiteShark</title>
    <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on theGreatWhiteShark</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 13:05:36 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A layman&#39;s guide to music production</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/recording/recording-mixing-mastering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 13:05:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/recording/recording-mixing-mastering/</guid>
      <description>During the past 10 years of making music, recording both mine and other people&amp;rsquo;s bands, and talking with countless musicians I picked up a lot of different facts and hints concerning music production. But it was basically just a collection of a lot of details, which did not made me see the bigger picture. So what was the purpose of mastering again? Is the DAW, which I use for recording my songs, sufficient for the mixing procedure?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching Hydrogen drum kits using Emacs</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/switching-hydrogen-drum-kits-using-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 14:23:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/switching-hydrogen-drum-kits-using-emacs/</guid>
      <description>As much as I like the Hydrogen drum machine, there are some details, which are quite annoying. One of those things is that you do not have a set commands, which help you to migrate from one drum kit to another.
The usual scenario is the following. You programmed a song and are curious how it would sound using a different drum kit. But just loading another one doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in many cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Wordpress to Github Pages&#43;Hugo</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/moving-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 22:27:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/moving-to-github/</guid>
      <description>I moved my blog from Wordpress to Github Pages.
In addition, I also decided to split the blog in three different parts. Art, coding, and music are just a little too diverse and I intend to do further posts in all of these subjects.
You can find the blogs via the following links
 music blog coding blog overall blog  Motivation First of all, I have to say: I had a nice time on Wordpress and it was a great place to start my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux audio</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 11:58:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/</guid>
      <description>Posts concerning the recording of audio in Linux systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music processing</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/music-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 11:58:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/music-processing/</guid>
      <description>Posts concerning the recording of audio in Linux systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/recording/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 11:58:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/recording/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 17:39:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a PhD student in physics, a passionated programmer, a vehement open-source user, a picky musician, and an aspiring artist.
In this blog I want to share my experiences, present the solutions I found to encountered problems, and maybe help some other people out there facing similar challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What spectra do tell us</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/music-processing/spectral-analysis-impact-of-the-amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/music-processing/spectral-analysis-impact-of-the-amp/</guid>
      <description>Of course I won&amp;rsquo;t provide conclusive answers to those questions. In truth, this is just my first, humble attempt to grow accustom to my equipment and its peculiarities and frequency responses. But one purpose of this blog is to document my projects and the bottom line of all of this is of course: it&amp;rsquo;s fun to dig into your music and audio signals using your computer. :)
Equipment and software I will use the software presented in my last post on spectral analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectral analysis</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/spectral-analysis-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/spectral-analysis-linux/</guid>
      <description>As a disclaimer: I will not write about the Fourier transform and spectra in general. For a very nice and gentle introduction I can recommend the second chapter of Fundamentals of Music Processing by Meinard Müller.
Setup As a prerequisite I assume you have the Non DAW Suite installed and JACK configured on your system. Now, power up JACK (e.g. via QjackCtl) and open Non Timeline.
For the sake of reproducibility I will use a gong sample provided by freewavesamples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ZynAddSubFx as sound synthesizer in TuxGuitar</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/zynaddsubfx-with-tuxguitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/zynaddsubfx-with-tuxguitar/</guid>
      <description>TuxGuitar configuration It&amp;rsquo;s fairly simple. Just start ZynAddSubFX and TuxGuitar right after each other. Now in TuxGuitar head to the menu entry Tools &amp;gt; Settings and choose the bottom tab Sound. As MIDI Sequencer choose TuxGuitar Sequencer and as MIDI Port choose ZynAddSubFX. This will wire up both programs and you can use them seamlessly from now on.
ZynAddSubFX configuration But to generate sounds using ZynAddSubFX you have to select an instrument first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording audio using Linux systems Pt. II</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/linux-sound-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/linux-sound-server/</guid>
      <description>After we got an overview about the peculiarities of the Linux system with respect to audio and recording in the last post we will dive some more into the Linux sound system itself. If you do not understand every last bit of information in here, don&amp;rsquo;t worry.
The Linux way of handling hardware I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go into too much detail here but instead just hook you up with the general concepts of hardware handling in Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording audio using Linux systems Pt. I</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/recording-audio-using-linux-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/recording-audio-using-linux-systems/</guid>
      <description>The reason I had a hard time back then was not a lack of good documentation or badly implemented software. No, quite the opposite. It was the vast amount of different choices I select. Which program to use for recording, which underlying sound server, should I use a real-time kernel or not&amp;hellip; And with every choice I made several new options popped up. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, this is the true power of the Linux system and enables advanced users to surpass everything they possible could accomplish with Windows or Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>