<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux-audio on theGreatWhiteShark</title>
    <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux-audio on theGreatWhiteShark</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 18:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectral analysis</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/spectral-analysis-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/spectral-analysis-linux/</guid>
      <description>A very important part of digital signal processing (DSP) as well as music processing is to analyze the spectrum and the spectrogram of your recording. Even Audacity already can handle it. So let&amp;rsquo;s use it with Non Timeline or a general JACK-based environment too.
In this blog post I will review the available software for creating spectra in Linux systems and how to deploy them. I will not write about the Fourier transform and spectra in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ZynAddSubFx as sound synthesizer in TuxGuitar</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/zynaddsubfx-with-tuxguitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/zynaddsubfx-with-tuxguitar/</guid>
      <description>Although not as good as the original GuitarPro, I really like TuxGuitar. After all, it is the only usable software to produce guitar tabs and scores in Linux systems I&amp;rsquo;m aware of. But of all its shortcomings the issues I had with its sound system were the worst: The sound generation is broken quite frequently and the whole program remains silent. In this short post I&amp;rsquo;ll explain to you how to replace the internal sound generator of TuxGuitar with ZynAddSubFX for a more stable and reliable setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording audio using Linux systems Pt. II</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/linux-sound-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/linux-sound-server/</guid>
      <description>After we got an overview about the peculiarities of the Linux system with respect to audio and recording in the last post we will dive some more into the Linux sound system itself.
As for most other Linux subsystems the audio one grew quite naturally too. So you have quite a number of alternatives and different ways to achieve a goal. Not just in using different software, but also in the underlying sound servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording audio using Linux systems Pt. I</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/recording-audio-using-linux-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/linux-audio/recording-audio-using-linux-systems/</guid>
      <description>As much as I love the Linux system, its incredible amount of free and open-source software and distributions, and the whole supportive community providing awesome documentation etc., the much pain it was to migrate all my music recording and mixing from Windows to Linux. It cost me numerous sleepless nights and resulted in some quite discouraging failures during my first year of diving into open-source.
The reason I had a hard time back then was not a lack of good documentation or badly implemented software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>