<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux-audio on theGreatWhiteShark</title>
    <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux-audio on theGreatWhiteShark</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 18:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectral analysis</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/spectral-analysis-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/spectral-analysis-linux/</guid>
      <description>As a disclaimer: I will not write about the Fourier transform and spectra in general. For a very nice and gentle introduction I can recommend the second chapter of Fundamentals of Music Processing by Meinard Müller.
Setup As a prerequisite I assume you have the Non DAW Suite installed and JACK configured on your system. Now, power up JACK (e.g. via QjackCtl) and open Non Timeline.
For the sake of reproducibility I will use a gong sample provided by freewavesamples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ZynAddSubFx as sound synthesizer in TuxGuitar</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/zynaddsubfx-with-tuxguitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/zynaddsubfx-with-tuxguitar/</guid>
      <description>TuxGuitar configuration It&amp;rsquo;s fairly simple. Just start ZynAddSubFX and TuxGuitar right after each other. Now in TuxGuitar head to the menu entry Tools &amp;gt; Settings and choose the bottom tab Sound. As MIDI Sequencer choose TuxGuitar Sequencer and as MIDI Port choose ZynAddSubFX. This will wire up both programs and you can use them seamlessly from now on.
ZynAddSubFX configuration But to generate sounds using ZynAddSubFX you have to select an instrument first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording audio using Linux systems Pt. II</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/linux-sound-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/linux-sound-server/</guid>
      <description>After we got an overview about the peculiarities of the Linux system with respect to audio and recording in the last post we will dive some more into the Linux sound system itself. If you do not understand every last bit of information in here, don&amp;rsquo;t worry.
The Linux way of handling hardware I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go into too much detail here but instead just hook you up with the general concepts of hardware handling in Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording audio using Linux systems Pt. I</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/recording-audio-using-linux-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.music.io/linux-audio/recording-audio-using-linux-systems/</guid>
      <description>The reason I had a hard time back then was not a lack of good documentation or badly implemented software. No, quite the opposite. It was the vast amount of different choices I select. Which program to use for recording, which underlying sound server, should I use a real-time kernel or not&amp;hellip; And with every choice I made several new options popped up. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, this is the true power of the Linux system and enables advanced users to surpass everything they possible could accomplish with Windows or Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>